Where I came from doesn't matter to me.
All I care about is living every
moment now to its fullest.
Hey, where is it? I don't see it at all.
Did you really spot it?
I definitely did.
That's the defining feature of being human.
I knew it. No picture books.
Zero Two feels the same way,
or so I thought.
I see it! Over there!
Goro was right. That's...
Yeah. The Garden.
Parasite Development Facility: Garden
This is the place known as
Garden, where we grew up.
It's a parasite development facility where
hundreds upon hundreds of children live.
Then there's this research hub that towers
over the Garden and looks down upon it.
Nursery 3: Laboratory
We called it the Lab.
I saw the Lab every day from afar,
but I'd never gone inside before.
Very, very few children actually
got to come here, right?
I think Hiro came here a few times.
Yeah. I was a designated special
research subject back then.
Peh. Damn teacher's pet.
And Mitsuru, too, I guess.
What? Mitsuru, too?
Listen up. The reason we're here
is to run tests on you all.
I'm sorry to say that this
won't be a homecoming.
You are hereby banned
from entering the Garden.
Tests?
What tests would need us
to come here, of all places?
I'm pretty sure we're just tagging along.
Code 002, you in particular
will undergo thorough testing.
I can't be bothered.
This is an order. We can't
put it off any longer.
Oh, hey!
If it isn't Nine Iota.
Fancy running into you here.
What a coincidence.
Or not. You're here for
maintenance, too, right?
Glad to see you haven't changed.
Who's that?
Beats me. But he's kinda hot.
These are the 9's, a special
forces unit APE directly controls.
Pleased to meet you.
APE Special Forces Unit: 9's
You guys are in the same
squad as Iota, right?
Please escort her to
you-know-where safe and sound.
"You-know-where"?
Surely you know where all the plantations
on this continent are currently headed.
I'll fill you in later.
Okay.
Anyway...
I'm relieved to see Iota's
fitting in with you guys.
Iota? You mean Zero Two?
Hey, we meet again.
That's right. She used to be one of us Nines.
Is that... so?
I thought she'd be too much for an ordinary
squad to handle, so I was surprised.
How did you manage to tame her?
"Tame"?
Zero Two is one of us.
Wow, she must've taken a real liking to you.
Never thought she'd play
buddy-buddy with humans.
I see the "special forces" haven't
been taught basic etiquette.
I fully realize now that I'd much rather
fight with Zero Two than you guys.
I see, I see.
You're a bit different from the
parasites in other squads, huh?
So that's why Iota's with you.
Wha...
Hey!
It's time to go, kids.
I've developed an interest in you guys, too.
I'd love to be part of your squad sometime.
Sadly, we only have space in the attic.
It wouldn't befit elites like you.
But if that's okay, you're welcome any time.
So proud and dignified...
Zero Two, did something happen recently?
Instead of bearing it all yourself,
why not talk to me?
Aren't we partners?
Kiss me.
Huh?
Kiss me now.
O-Okay...
Zero Tw-
Never mind.
I'm done.
You were right. They only ran
the simplest of tests on us.
I said don't touch me!
Get away from me!
I'm thinking of going to
the Garden after this.
What? We're forbidden from going there.
I want to let Naomi know I found a partner.
Damn you!
Don't cause any more trouble for me.
You all didn't have to come along.
Sorry, Futoshi.
It's fine! You're always welcome!
It wouldn't be fair if you
got to sneak out by yourself.
Yeah. And we're here now anyway,
so we might as well.
Ichigo, did you finish reading this?
Yeah, but I didn't get it at all.
Same here.
This book mentions a "holy tree."
Holy tree?
Apparently, it's talking about the mistletoe.
I hear there's one in the Garden, too.
I hope I get to see it someday.
It hasn't even been six months
since we left this place, right?
Yet it feels like the distant past.
Come with me.
I-Is that how we used to be?
I-I don't think so.
That was the same type of injection
as the ones we were administered.
They're starting to give parasite
injections to kids so young?
Indeed.
We've started injecting more concentrated
doses of yellow blood cells than before.
The klaxosaurs have grown
more active lately, you know?
So the system's being retooled to produce
more capable and obedient parasites.
Also...
You're the parasites of Squad 13, yes?
I'm pretty sure you aren't allowed in here.
Um, has a girl from
Plantation 13 named Naomi-
Code 703 been back here?
Code 703? No.
Once a parasite leaves
this place, they never return.
I had a feeling that'd be the case.
Aw, we were thrown out.
Where'd Naomi go, then?
Thinking back, that's how it always was.
In this facility, several children
who lived with us vanished one day.
We asked the adults about it,
but they wouldn't tell us a thing.
So I eventually came to realize
that none of us would ever become adults.
A mistletoe...
This really is the place!
Have I been here before?
Why'd Hiro ask us to head back before him?
Where's he going this time?
Beats me.
Where do you think we came from?
Huh?
Where'd that come from? Papa and
the rest made us, obviously.
Is that really true?
You're being kinda weird, Kokoro.
You kids!
I've never seen any children disobey
orders and get yelled at before.
You guys are truly interesting.
Go mess with someone else.
How cold.
We're leaving soon, so what's
a little chat going to hurt?
I hear you guys are a test
team formed by Dr. Franxx.
Is that why you're given so much
more freedom than the other squads?
What kind of tests are you running?
I'd love to hear the details.
Of Iota's partners, only Code 016 has
managed to ride with her more than thrice.
Is that related to your tests?
What are you trying to say?
You finally looked my way.
I'll let you in on a big secret.
What Code 002 is really like.
She can never coexist with you.
She's just wearing a human guise
and pretending she can.
Five Moho-class klaxosaurs.
They aren't much of a threat, but...
The question is why they showed up here, huh?
No klaxosaurs have ever been
sighted in this area before.
Did they notice what we're up to?
All FRANXX, prepare to sortie.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Zero Two, your horns...
Quit staring.
S-Sorry...
Darling,
let's kill a whole lot of
klaxosaurs again today.
Zero Two!
Strelizia, follow the plan!
You're being too direct.
Oh, shut up.
I'll kill them all! Isn't that enough?
Hiro, four o'clock!
Damn...
Pay more attention to our surroundings!
Why, you...
You're chasing them too far.
We have to work with the others.
They're fast!
Strelizia! There's more coming your way!
I'll pulverize them all together!
Listen to me!
Zero Two!
Damn it!
Why? Why are you getting
in my way, too, Darling?
Fire!
We got through it... somehow.
Damn monsters.
Take this.
And this.
Zero Two...
That's enough! You don't
need to hit them anymore!
Damn you! Damn you!
I'm going to kill you all
and become human.
We're out of fuel?
Don't you think you went too far?
That was kinda scary.
Zero Two...
Your nails are peeling off!
You're bruised all over!
Let go.
...ill them.
Huh?
I'm running out of time.
I need to kill more klaxosaurs.
Many, many more.
I wanna hurry up and become human.
You mentioned that earlier.
What did you mean?
I'm going to be human...
A human.
Pull yourself together, Zero Two!
I don't know why you're
so fixated on being human,
but you are who you are!
It doesn't matter where you were born!
Your horns and fangs aren't an issue, either!
Shut your damn mouth!
I was attracted to the person you are!
It doesn't matter whether
you're human or not.
This entire time, I'd been trying to
figure out why I felt this way about you,
and watching Goro and Futoshi helped
me understand this unique feeling.
I love you, Zero Two!
I love you as you are!
You love me? What's that supposed to mean?
What are you...
Oh, is this it?
This is what you're talking about, right?
I'll teach you what comes after kissing.
That's not it! I...
No! You're wrong, Zero Two!
This isn't what I mean!
I...
This is tedious.
Hurry up and let it all out.
This isn't enough.
Kill more of those monsters
and make me human.
You're only my fodder, after all!
Fodder?
Detailed testing has shown
that Code 002's saurification has
accelerated since they became partners.
Code 016's numbers are close
to the upper limit, too.
If this keeps up, he might undergo
a genetic transformation.
You mean he could no longer be called human?
Zero Two, I need to talk to-
Don't show me.
Don't reflect me!
Wh-What are you doing?
Why do you think Iota is
called the Partner Killer?
It's because she places her partners
under a curse that drains their life away.
That power is what she uses
to operate the FRANXX.
And she can do that because she's
the key to saving the world.
The key to saving the world?
Just from what I know, she's used and
discarded more than a hundred stamens.
Code 016 is an exceptional case.
Maybe he has a special ability
that keeps him going.
But if he keeps riding with her,
the curse might turn him into the
same kind of monster that she is.
She must believe that the
more klaxosaurs she kills,
the closer she'll get to being human.
Hiro!
Strelizia!
Outta my way!
I'll kill many, many more and become human!
You're wrong, Zero Two!
You can't become human that way!
What's driving your obsession?
Don't. Don't tie me down.
Damn it! Look at me, Zero Two!
Just quietly be devoured
like the fodder you are!
Stop!
Zero... Two...
Give me all of your life.
I'm going to become human
so I can meet my darling from back then.
Dar... ling?
Para-capacity has crossed critical
point and is still rising.
This is bad.
The saurification will begin!
What's going on?
Someone's thoughts are flowing into my mind.
When was it?
I've seen this before.
Hands clasped together, and eyes
filled with hatred for the world.
A girl with red skin and blue blood.
Ah, I remember now.
That's... She's...
That's right.
I'm a monster in disguise.
Episode 12
The Garden Where It All Began