"This will surely be our last battle."
That's what everyone believed.
But while the rest had those thoughts
running through their heads,
a different emotion had
begun lurking inside me,
and I didn't know what to do with it.
I'm going to stay behind.
Mitsuru...
You've chosen this battlefield, huh?
Why did you stay behind?
You could've found another
partner and gone with them.
I stayed because I wanted to.
It's my responsibility to see this through.
Responsibility?
When you don't remember a thing?
I told you, I don't expect anything from you.
So don't mind me.
Grand Klaxosaur Fleet
Mothership Klaxosaur
You okay, Zorome?
These are some crazy Gs! My guts
feel like they're crumpling up!
And this is after the G-Canceler's
abating a lot of it, apparently.
Seriously?
I don't know why, but this
feels just right somehow.
I can move a lot more freely.
Yeah. Fighting in space
should be no problem at all.
And check out these weapons.
After all this time,
we get identical loadouts?
It's like we're a real team now.
We've always been a real team, you dope.
Have we?
We're really in space, huh?
Yeah. So far from home.
New space equipment for the FRANXX,
and all these provisions on the ship.
What if Hiro was right, and the klaxosaurs
really did leave all of this for us?
That would mean humanity has been allowed
to join the fight to defend Earth.
Do we really have the right to?
If we want to ensure humanity's survival,
all we can do is believe.
We really connected...
Like I said, we Nines can
be both stamens and pistils.
Besides, you put too much
strain on your partner.
No ordinary pistil could handle it.
You're not exactly in the best shape, either.
Don't push yourself.
Gee, thanks for the timely warning.
Anyway, give me a taste of what you can do!
You want to go see Iota, don't you?
Wait, this feels almost like...
Of course it does.
We're Iota's clones.
It's funny how my final partner is a human.
All FRANXX, return to ship.
We'll be accelerating to
cruising speed shortly.
Roger.
What do your eyes see?
Everyone's out fighting in space,
but I've lost the ability to fight with them.
I'm not a parasite anymore.
You understand this?
Somewhat.
How are the controls so similar?
Perhaps klaxo sapiens weren't
all that different from humans.
That said, most of the navigation
system is automated.
We're only tagging along
for the ride, basically.
What is this route leading to?
What are we going to find in Mars orbit?
Who knows?
But Apus is heading there as we speak.
Looks like getting there won't be easy.
For some reason, I don't want those
kids to hurt themselves any more.
Isn't that weird?
I mean, I watched over them
as tools of warfare for so long.
Is feeling that way really so wrong?
The children's sole purpose
in life was to fight.
If this truly is their final battle,
don't you think they'll need someone
like you in their lives ahead?
Yo.
Hey.
Goro... Ichigo...
We've always been attached at the hip,
and now we're even in space together.
Let's get to Zero Two, no matter what.
Yeah.
C'mon, Goro. Don't you have something to say?
Uh... Sorry I hit you.
What the heck?
Forget it.
If you're gonna apologize, you shouldn't
have done it in the first place.
Oh, shut it.
Detecting what seems to be a VIRM fleet.
All FRANXX, prepare for combat!
It's not slowing down?!
Is it going to plow through to where Apus is?
The VIRM are trying to surround Apus.
The klaxosaurs are forming a
defensive line around it, too.
And we're charging right in there?
Damn it!
Aren't we gonna fight back?
All the energy output is
focused on the shield.
The ship's going to ignore the enemy
and head straight for Apus!
Over there!
We can see it now.
Strelizia Apus!
Hiro?!
All units, follow Alpha's lead!
Roger!
Here we go, guys!
There's a huge number
of VIRM units near Apus.
Be careful.
Why isn't Apus firing that huge laser?
If it could, it would've already.
Maybe it really isn't fully
operational without a stamen.
Incoming!
Scatter and take them out!
Hiro!
Ignore the enemy and head to Apus!
Zorome!
Right on!
Follow me!
Leave the enemies in front to us!
Eat that!
Chlorophytum!
We've got your backs!
What the...
Don't forget about us.
Get back and relax.
Hah! Like I'd let you hospital
runaways do all the work!
Look!
They're trying to keep us away from Apus.
Did they realize Hiro's with us?
It'll be bad news if they block us off.
Hiro, use your FRANXX's speed to cut through.
We'll cover you.
Got it.
Zorome! Miku!
Don't push it!
If we don't push ourselves now...
...then when will we?!
Go!
Hiro!
We caught up!
Look there.
It's the entrance.
All right!
What?
Why, you!
If that's not gonna work...
Well, this is not good.
Looks like this is as far as I go with you.
Meeting you guys helped me learn
a little about being human.
But my home is the battlefield,
and nowhere else.
Say hi to Iota for me.
Alpha!
It's been kinda fun, I guess.
Mars Orbit
Zero Two, why'd you leave
me and run off alone?
Together, we are one.
We'll always be together.
Didn't we promise each other that?
Answer me, Zero Two.
No!
You can't. What's the matter?
Zero Two!
What is happening to you?
No!
Zero Two...
Is that you?
If it is,
then please...
Eat me.
Is this the picture book in Zero Two's mind?
Stay away.
Why'd you come?
To see you.
Why'd you leave?
I want you to remain human.
I want to be with you.
I can't be with you.
Why?
I just can't.
The ship!
Hey, look!
Crap!
Let's go provide backup, guys!
Not letting us go without a fight, huh?
We'll distract them!
Go!
Thanks!
Shall we go out in a blaze of glory, then?
Not a bad idea.
Let's move to another ship!
This is it, huh...
Leave me and go.
You don't get to tell me
that after keeping me alive.
To hell with that!
It's your duty to watch
over their futures, too!
What's that?
That ship was equipped with a bomb?
Cease your resistance.
That voice...
Is there any point at all to this warfare?
All lifeforms will eventually merge with us.
Surrender yourself to the gentle,
perpetual pleasure we offer.
Our utopia is free of all hatred
and discrimination between species.
Klaxosaurs? Humanity?
Such distinctions won't matter anymore.
Equality for all!
And beyond it all, we will attain
an endless and peaceful slumber,
and at the same time,
endless and relentless evolution.
Rejecting that to march toward your
destruction is far too foolish.
Now, become one with us.
To the adults, that may well
have sounded like utopia.
But that isn't where the children belong.
The flames of their lives will never
burn as bright in perpetual tranquility!
It isn't a matter of right or wrong.
This is simply the path that the children,
and humanity, have chosen!
This is pretty rough.
How much longer is Hiro gonna take?
Don't worry. He's always pulled through.
And we're not the only ones.
Yeah! Those two must be
fighting back on Earth, too!
Right!
Kokoro!
It's not safe here! Get inside!
Leave us be!
She wants to stay right here!
But it's not good for your body!
I'm going to protect her!
I'm not a parasite anymore.
I have nothing left.
There's nothing I can do!
So I want to at least be by her side!
So please let me stay.
Then I'll stay right here with you two!
Leave me alone!
I've told you so many times,
you don't need to feel responsib-
It's not about responsibility!
Please don't say you have nothing.
If you don't have anything,
then neither do I!
But I've found my reason to live.
I want to protect you and that baby's future.
I'm a weakling!
And I don't really understand
what love is, either.
But I can keep walking if I'm with you.
That's what I've come to believe.
Why do you still have that?
Why do you say my name,
even though it hurts you?
Even without our memories,
we can start all over again.
I'll call your name as many times as you want!
That is our battle.
Mitsuru... Mitsuru...
Mitsuru!
Kokoro... Kokoro...
Kokoro!
Mitsuru!
I was always a monster, so whatever.
But you? I want you to live as a human.
That's why I can't be with you.
We promised we'd always be together.
Stay away.
I'm fine by myself.
Liar.
If you really are, then why
is your last page left blank?
Don't fly off alone.
Let me stay with you.
Let's rewrite that story's ending together.
Darling...
Zero Two?
Wh-What's going on?
I hereby vow to never let you go.
Okay.
Strelizia
True Apus
Zero Two!
I'm so glad Hiro got to see her.
Wait, what?
Satellite
Phobos
Deimos
That's...
What the heck is that?
A warp gate.
A warp gate?
Yeah. The klaxo sapiens
built it a long time ago.
Listen up, guys.
Zero Two and I are going to go through
that gate and leave the Solar System.
Leave the Solar System?
What? Now?
Don't tell me...
Whoa, wait up! What are you talking about?
You met up with Zero Two,
so why not head back to Earth?
Apus and the gate's system are linked.
Neither Zero Two nor I
can stop the process now.
Besides, the gate will close soon.
You're kidding me.
This can't be happening.
But why?
Why do you two have to go?
To put an end to this war.
So that's what the bomb was for, huh?
Then let's all go!
You can't.
Only Apus can withstand
going through the gate.
But what are you gonna do all by yourselves?
The enemy's main force will be
much larger than this one, right?
Yeah. That's why we have
to take them by surprise.
You will come back, right?
No...
I won't let you go!
If that's your answer,
I'm not letting you go!
Leader's orders!
Come back alive, both of you!
Ichigo...
Exactly! I won't stand for it, either!
Come back to us, Hiro!
I'm not gonna accept a goodbye like this!
Yeah! Squad 13 isn't complete
without the two of you!
So come back with Zero Two!
Right.
You guys...
Zero Two.
It doesn't matter how long it takes.
Make sure you come back with Hiro.
We'll build a home and wait for you!
You're always so bossy.
I promise I'll come back to you.
Together with my darling.
Everyone has their own feelings and desires.
We're all looking for somewhere we belong.
Strelizia looked so beautiful
at that moment,
or so everyone who saw
it would tell us later.
Right now, all we can do is pray
that what awaits those two
is a happy ending.
Episode 23
DARLING in the FRANXX