Had I really forgotten all this time?
How did I forget something so important?
You were the girl...
with the picture book back then, weren't you?
You saw?
I'm sorry... I...
I didn't remember.
But our minds linked.
This happened before, too.
Even then,
you were waiting under that tree...
for me.
How...
Darling!
Hey, were you my darling from back then?
Then what have I been doing all this time?
Get your hands off of Hiro!
Hiro! Hiro!
H-Hey, you okay?
Pull yourself together, Hiro!
"I want you to speak your mind with me."
Hiro, hang in there!
"I want to get to know you better."
He often told me he wanted
us to understand each other.
I couldn't comprehend what
he was trying to say.
But I think I get it now.
I think I know what he was looking for.
Come to me, as our inhibitions crumble
Please don't fear me
The flightless bird dreams of a sky
Whose colors blend into
the wrong shade of red
I tried to block out the banging on my door
Are you one banging on it?
Or is it someone else?
Will your lips taste the kiss of death?
Darling, our destiny
courses through our veins
A change is sweeping across
the world... Is it love?
I want us to come together
more than anyone, darling
Please don't fear me
Kiss me now
APE Hospital Room
It looks like he's at the end of his rope.
His yellow blood cell count has gone far
beyond what the human body can handle.
It's so high, his saurification
could begin any moment now.
His mind is clearly hazy, too.
Did he connect to 002's mind too
deeply via Strelizia and hallucinate?
Either way, he's in a perilous condition.
I thought Hiro might be able to handle it,
but it's time to call this off.
I'll talk to my darling.
Wait.
Hey! I'm talking to you!
That way...
I said wait!
Don't stop me. I need to see my darling.
Hey, Ichigo?
You can't be serious!
Do you realize who put
Hiro in that hospital bed?
You're not getting anywhere
near Hiro ever again.
C-Calm down, Ichigo.
She must be worried about him too, you know.
Yeah.
Why are you getting so worked up, Ichigo?
All this time, you've deceived
Hiro and exploited him.
And you just tried to make
him lose his humanity.
"Lose his humanity"?
I heard all about it.
You suck up your partner's life
and discard them once you're done.
And you've killed many, many people that way!
Who told you that?
I overheard Nana and Hachi, too.
They said that if this keeps up,
Hiro can no longer be called human.
Is that true, Zero Two?
Of course not, right?
It has to be a misunderstanding.
You two have managed just fine so far.
Shut up.
What I do to my darling is
none of your damn business.
So you admit it?
Happy now? Just let me see my darling.
At first, I had my misgivings about
having you as part of our team.
But you started to fit in,
and I thought we had finally
become teammates.
Teammates?
I couldn't care less about that.
Outta my way already.
Well, I don't care how you feel.
I'm never letting you see Hiro again.
You've been deceiving him
and us this whole time.
You have no place here anymore!
Hiro!
Thank goodness!
Hey.
A triumphant return, huh?
Man...
I thought you were a goner this time!
Ow.
Good job surviving!
They said that if you get some rest,
you'll be as good as new in no time.
Aren't you glad, Hiro?
Yeah.
Hey, where's Zero Two?
She isn't here.
I didn't let her come.
You know why, don't you?
But don't worry.
We'll keep you safe,
so get some rest for now.
Ichigo...
See ya, Hiro.
Take care.
S-Sure.
Later.
Make sure you eat, okay?
Mitsuru.
What did you want to talk about?
I made a promise to you way back,
before you got an Elixir Injection, right?
After that, I...
Never mind that. It was a long time ago.
Even I'd forgotten about it until now.
Really?
Yes.
Any other stamen would've died long ago.
I see you've still got the devil's luck.
Listen to Ichigo, learn your lesson,
and stay away from Zero Two.
But...
There's still something I must ask her.
There you go, poking your
nose into trouble again.
That part of you hasn't changed a bit.
Thanks, Mitsuru.
"Ask her," huh?
After that day, my aptitude
score kept going down.
And finally...
Code 703 and Code 016.
You fail.
My life ended once already.
But through meeting Zero Two...
I did it...
I'm piloting a FRANXX!
Still...
Given that no other stamen could handle it,
why was I the only one?
I'm sure you'll be fine next time,
the time after that, and many more times.
There's only one reason I can think of.
Now... let me get a taste of you.
You are now...
My darling!
Did you know all along that
I could only ride with you?
I have to ask.
I must make sure.
You have your next mission.
HQ has sent official orders.
Plantation 13 has been heading
toward a certain place for a while.
This is our destination.
Your mission is to neutralize every
klaxosaur inhabiting this structure,
and take control of this area.
Furthermore,
this is a joint operation with the 9's
and FRANXX squads from each plantation.
A joint operation?
The opening salvo will be
fired 27 hours from now.
Squad 13 is scheduled to
be part of the sixth wave.
Get it over with already.
Unlike other times, the enemy
will counter with numbers.
This will, without a doubt, be your
most difficult operation to date.
Focus on the task-
Ichigo?
Please remove Code 002 from
Squad 13 as of this mission.
Ichigo, the thing is...
If this request isn't granted,
Squad 13 will not participate
in the operation.
This is our squad's decision as a whole.
We can't fight with her anymore.
Zero Two was set to return to the
9's as of this mission, anyway.
Wait a second!
Where'd that come from?
Don't go deciding things for me!
HQ has already given this the green light.
We can't keep you here any longer.
What about my darling?
Wh-Where are you going?
Sorry, but you're not going to his room.
We won't let you see Hiro, no matter what.
Why?
Sorry, Hiro.
Get back to your bed.
Uh, but...
Please.
Why?
Why is everyone getting in my way?
All I want to do is see my darling
and talk to him.
How are you feeling?
A lot better.
I see. Glad to hear it.
How are things with you?
Well...
I brought an apple. Want to eat it?
Zero Two's going back to the 9's.
When?
Tomorrow night.
We have a big mission coming up.
You hate me, don't you?
I know you want to see her.
But I can't let you.
If you do, you'll never be the same again.
The others are worried, too.
We're a team now. We don't
want to lose anyone.
So please, Hiro.
I don't care if you hate me,
but please don't go anywhere.
Sorry, Ichigo.
Mitsuru told me I poke my nose
into trouble too much.
I made all of you worry, didn't I?
Y-You don't have to apologize.
That's the good thing about you.
I've always found that side of you...
Ouch!
Ow...
You okay?
Y-Yeah...
Yikes, that's a deep cut.
There. All set.
H-Hard to tell who's the patient here, huh?
Seriously.
You're always so clumsy, Ichigo.
Th-That was just bad luck!
Really? What about this, then?
That's... a bunny.
A bunny? This thing?
Sh-Shut up! Look, I'm gradually
getting better at it!
This one here is really
close to the real thing!
And this one kinda sorta
almost looks like ears...
I thought we had finally
become teammates.
You have no place here anymore!
I always knew...
No matter how I disguised myself as
a human, I could never be one of you.
That's why I wanted to
kill lots more klaxosaurs
and become human already.
For that, I...
But even then, my darling's all I have!
Thanks for that.
I think I'll get some sleep now.
Right. S-Sorry to stay so long.
I'll have them clean it all up later,
so you can leave it there.
Really?
Please do, then.
See you, Hiro.
Take care.
H-Hey!
Hold it!
Stop!
Yeah! Get back to your room!
Hey, Zero Two! What are you-
Hey, are you okay?
Ow...
Wh-What's going on here?
Uh...
Well...
Don't stop me.
I'm going to see my darling.
Would you give it a rest already?
You'll see him, and then what?
You'll lie to him again, right?
No! You're wrong!
I just want to talk to him!
Let her go, Ichigo.
Listen to her. She must have something
really important to discuss.
Goro... But she's...
I agree.
We can't force them apart.
I feel so sorry for them.
You can meet Hiro, Zero Two,
but we're all going to be there.
Are you okay with that?
Huh?
What's going on here?
How's Hiro?
Probably sleeping.
It's really quiet.
We're coming in, Hiro.
Darli-
Why?
No way!
I kept watch the entire time!
Look at that.
That guy...
He got out from there?
He's so reckless.
Hiro...
Why?
You tricked me.
You lied to me.
N-No, Zero Two! We didn't mean to!
Hiro must've... I know!
He must've gone to see you!
Shut your mouth!
Zero Two, it's me.
I, um... want to ask you something.
And I want to talk to you about something.
Remember when you said you
weren't afraid to die?
I'm the same.
But that's why I want to
make sure of several things.
Did you...
Did you use me, knowing all along?
Zero Two?
Isn't she in?
What is all this?
Humans are so weak!
Get it now? Never stand in my way-
Zero Two!
Darling.
What are you doing?
I finally got to see you, darling.
There's something I want
to talk to you about.
Ichigo!
You okay?
Ichigo? Ichigo!
Hiro...
Run away.
Why would you do this?!
"Why"?
You asked me to speak my
mind with you, remember?
But these guys just wouldn't let me.
So I...
No...
Let's talk lots and lots, okay?
It's not too late. We can still take it back...
Zero Two...
At this moment, you truly are a monster.
You aren't human.
This is punishment.
I set up the boy who was the
sole reason I wanted to be human
and tried to make him the
same kind of monster as me.
So this is my punishment.
This was for the best, Hiro.
Let's head inside.
I won't let you!
I'm not letting you go!
If you go back to her,
you'll turn into a monster!
You won't be the same ever again!
I'd rather die than let that happen!
But...
Welcome home, Nine Iota.
Take a look. The doctor brought
them all here for you.
Use as many as you like.
I don't regret the kiss we
shared during the mock battle.
I want to be with you forever!
I'll make it so I can ride you
with you this time, I swear!
I can do anything for you.
It's true.
I mean, I've always...
You've always been my everything.
Ever since we were kids,
I've always, always had eyes for you alone.
I...
I love you, Hiro!
Episode 14
Punishment and Confession