Almost done. Let's gang up and end it in one.
What is this? Gross!
It's all sticky!
But...
It doesn't hurt.
Yeah, seems fine.
So it's just for show?
How dare you spew this
disgusting gunk all over us?!
Let's try it again, guys. Stick to the plan.
What the heck?
K-Kokoro!
Why are you spacing out, Zorome?
Hey, you listening to me?
Y-Yeah. It's nothing, really.
Futoshi?
Don't worry. It's nothing at all.
Focus. We're in the middle of a battle.
I-I know!
Let's finish it off, darling!
Huh? Y-Yeah.
Darling?
This is bad, Zero Two!
It's gonna be exposed!
Don't tell her, dumbass!
My parasite suit!
You've got the wrong idea!
We only didn't tell you because we didn't
want to distract you during the battle.
As for me,
I simply found you amazingly
beautiful, Kokoro!
Believe me! This is straight from the heart!
So stupid.
Y'know, it's not like being
seen hurts you or anything.
Excuse me? What did you just say?
Wait, guys.
Zero Two told me that parasites are, uh...
better off being a little pervy!
Right, Zero Two?
Yup, yup.
What the hell?
I can't believe they've been ogling us.
Wait, were they doing it
back at the beach, too?
That's how boys are.
Unbelievable! They're such creeps!
And here I thought we'd finally
started to link up well.
This is a matter that can
deeply affect squad morale.
All of you need to calm down a little.
I've had it! I don't wanna be
anywhere near the boys anymore!
I know what to do. We should quit.
Let's put an end to our communal
life with the boys!
Bath and Changing Area
No Boys Allowed!!
Listen up.
Boys are banned from
setting foot on this side.
Wh-Who died and made you
the boss? This is messed up!
Zorome.
Cross that line, and you will regret it.
Ah, puberty.
It's unprecedented for so many members
of a squad to hit puberty at once.
Statistics indicate that it has always
been at most one or two together.
But this time, it's practically everyone.
It's clearly an abnormal case.
But that's what makes it so intriguing.
If we go by APE's manual, we should
intervene and resolve the issue immediately.
Listen to yourself. What would be the
point of this test team if we did that?
Just observe what happens and
give me detailed reports.
Don't you dare interfere
or let the geezers know.
Did you see the look on the
boys' faces back there?
Serves them right!
What's the matter?
Now we've just gotta rein her in.
H-Hey, what do you think you're doing?
Well, seeing as we can't use the
bath, we took a dip in the lake.
It felt amazing.
W-Would it kill you to get dressed?
Are you listening to me?
What we do in our territory
is none of your damn business.
What was that all about?!
They're trying to provoke us.
I bet it was Goro's idea.
Zorome and Futoshi couldn't
have thought of it.
They get to have fun in the lake,
and we're stuck cleaning the bath?
It's not fair!
We can't really complain about that.
We're the ones who declared
the bath off-limits to the boys.
I know, but still!
Man, why must cleaning be the only
thing we have to do ourselves?
I wish the invisible caretakers would handle it,
like they do with our food and laundry!
Sorry, but we've taken over this area.
We noticed that you girls
hadn't taped it off.
So good!
Today's breakfast is extraordinary!
No fair! You're heartless!
You're right.
So what say we both drop all the
silly rules and eat together?
It's a trap.
Agreed.
Don't go, Miku!
No!
Talk about pigheaded.
Everyone's gotten too stubborn about this.
This is looking really bad. We need
to hurry up and do something.
Is that how you feel, darling?
I'm the opposite.
I think it could use a
little spicing up, in fact.
Could it be you have an interest in plants?
Not really.
Then why are you here?
This place is the perfect getaway
when I want to be alone. That's all.
I begged Nana to let me take
care of this greenhouse.
We had seeds, so I've been planting and
growing them while studying up on things.
Have you ever heard of
the language of flowers?
This is a hibiscus. Its floral
meaning is "delicate beauty."
And the cattleya over
there stands for "alluring."
Hey, do you really not mind
chatting with me like this?
Are you talking about the fight?
It's stupid. I can't be bothered to play along.
Really? That's so cool!
Cool?
It takes a lot of courage
to refuse to toe the line.
I was too scared to say anything.
Your First Childbirth
- What's Best for Your Baby -
You brought it back with you?
Y-Yeah...
Not that it matters to me.
I'm starving.
And whose fault is that?
Hey, that's why I'm looking
for things to eat, isn't it?
So this is what the first floor's like.
I've never come here before.
It's sealed off.
Nobody's using it?
How long will this fight go on?
Well... I wouldn't mind if
things stayed this way forever.
I taste a secret.
What?!
Wait!
Whose side are you on?
We'd like you to cooperate, if you could.
What you're doing is lame.
You're just playing around.
Wha... You don't know that!
Believe it or not, we're serious.
H-Hey...
You're serious, huh?
All right. I'll join you.
Bath and Changing Area
No Boys Allowed!!
Huh?
What's up?
They said you can use the bath now.
Girls Bathing
Boys Bathing
Zero Two said it was okay
for us to use the bath?
Really?
Really. The girls must've
waved the white flag.
Wait! I-It's not what it looks like!
Hear us out! It was Zero Two!
Crap. We can't stop them now.
Stop!
Why would you do this, Zero Two?
This is a real fight. Come at
me with all you've got, darling.
We were set up!
Enough excuses!
Hold it!
Hurry up and catch me if you can, darling!
You're on!
Perverts! You horny perverts!
Fiends! I'm gonna break you in half!
We should leave for now.
Hey, our clothes are gone!
What?!
This is it. There's nowhere
left for you to run-
Darling, you pervert!
Why'd you do this, though?
The fight. I wanted to try
taking part in a human fight.
Zero Two...
Hey, darling, do I seem
a little more human now?
Zero Two!
That's it! We've had it with this crap!
We're the ones running out of patience!
Shut up! Don't look down on us boys!
Why don't you try sparing
a thought for us girls?!
Shut up! All of you-
Knock it off!
What were you going to do if
klaxosaurs attacked right now?
Can you really sortie like this?
I certainly don't think so.
You're parasites. Don't forget
what comes first and foremost.
Yes, sir.
Could they be any more
unlike the other children?
I wasn't expecting Zero Two to join in, too.
I had so much fun!
I loved how naughty and rebellious that was!
What were you thinking? Explain yourself.
If you keep half-assing things like that,
you'll end up like the adults one day.
If you have anything you wanna say,
you'd better spit it out while you can.
Because you're all going
to die sooner or later.
I'm so pissed off!
Why are the girls so condescending, anyway?
They look down on us boys, obviously.
Nobody asked for a calm
and composed analysis!
Damn it. Screw it, I'm done.
I'm through with the girls.
I feel bad saying this, but I
thought that was kind of fun.
What?!
Zero Two was laughing her heart out,
like she was enjoying herself.
I'd never spared much thought
for how girls felt before now...
Why bother? They're weirdo whack jobs.
Yeah, I don't get them at all.
But that's exactly why I started
wanting to know more about her.
That way, I might be able
to offer her more support.
If you're talking about Zero Two,
you're barking up the wrong tree.
She's the ultimate pistil.
She doesn't need your support.
No, Zero Two is a normal girl.
And it's not just her.
Pistils let us stamens
handle all the controls,
but their frail bodies are the ones
bearing the brunt of each battle.
Oh, yeah. That must be rough.
Even so, they connect to the
FRANXX and do their best,
placing all their trust in us.
Watching her like that
really made me think...
I want to be stronger and
take better care of her.
Well, the girls are always
giving it their all in battle.
And if we ogle them while they are...
Of course they'd hate it.
Hey, I'm a man, too.
Even I feel the need to look after
my partner and take care of her.
And I don't wanna see any
of them in pain, either.
That means there's only
one thing for us to do.
"Die sooner or later," huh?
H-Hey, you know what?
I really think this can't go on!
There are things that we can't do alone,
but can do if we work with the boys!
And there are lots of things
like that, aren't there?
Piloting the FRANXX is one of them!
Yeah, the boys are perverts, and I have
no idea what goes through their heads.
Boys and girls are nothing alike, but that's
why it's good for us to be together!
After all, that's how...
uh... it's born, I think.
You know, like... the future, hope, and stuff.
So... so...
It's really unusual for
you to be so assertive.
Yeah, it surprised me.
What you said did sting, though.
We can't just be the ones who
complain all the time.
W-Wait a second! Are you
thinking of forgiving the boys?
Well, we won't get anywhere as things stand.
Oh, really? Suit yourselves, then!
I'm not letting this go,
even if I'm left all alone!
Wait, Miku!
I'm not gonna beg and plead
for forgiveness, okay?
You're still going on about that?
Goro...
Miku's missing.
Please help us find her.
What?
Miku! Hey!
Miku!
Hey, Miku!
Miku?
Miku!
Come on out!
Listen to that. They've all made up already.
Well, I'm still not leaving this room.
Is this...
No...
Miku!
Thank goodness. We were so worried.
What's wrong?
What's this room?
Probably one of the rooms the
former Squad 13 parasites used.
Former...
...Squad 13?
Oh, of course this plantation had a defensive
squad before we were assigned here.
So how come they aren't here now?
Why's that?
They were wiped out, obviously.
They couldn't come back alive.
We won't survive unless we all
get to know each other better.
Let's make up, guys.
Well...
I'm sorry, okay? I apologize!
I'll try my best not to leer at you anymore.
I bet you'll fail.
I'm way too cute, after all.
So you can do it a little,
but don't take it too far.
O-Okay, then...
The vase by the window had lilacs in it.
What were the former Squad 13 parasites
thinking when they placed them there?
There's no way for us to find out now,
but the next day, we went back and
replaced them with fresh lilacs.
In the language of flowers, lilacs represent
friendship, fond memories, and youth.
Would you cut it out?
I didn't do anything!
You were ogling me again, weren't you?
I was not!
Ugh!
Zero Two, I want you to speak
your mind with me from now on.
Oh? Why is that?
Because I want to get to know you better.
Darling... Grab on to me
and never let go, okay?
Episode 8
Boys x Girls