The act of bringing two pairs of lips
together, which we'd never heard of,
was called a kiss, she said.
Commence connecting.
The day after the klaxosaur attack,
the startup ritual picked up where it left
off, but in much quieter circumstances.
Papa and the other adults weren't
around to witness it anymore.
I was told the huge FRANXX
I rode was named Strelizia.
I had no recollection of anything
that happened after I got in,
but I still believe that
it all really happened,
and that I was able to
fly under my own power.
I'm no longer a nestling.
So I swore never to run away again.
Residential Quarter for Parasites: "Mistilteinn"
Parasite Boarding House
Meow?
Are mew from around here?
Ichigo?
H-Hiro?!
You didn't have to wait out here for me.
It's your fault for running off
first thing in the morning.
Awkward as it is, you're staying here now.
Hold your head high,
and make yourself at home.
I heard Naomi was all right.
She got taken to the hospital.
Yeah, I heard.
Were you the one piloting that FRANXX?
I don't really remember.
So I want to ride it again to make sure.
Again? That girl isn't part
of our squad, you know.
I don't care, as long as I get to pilot.
I heard the rumors about her.
None of her partners could ever ride
with her more than three times.
They didn't make it out alive.
I don't know if that's true or not,
but I think you should stay away from her.
But if I can't pilot,
I'm as good as dead anyway.
Hiro...
Hey, Hiro. Get inside quick.
That girl's in our mess hall.
Why is she still here?
Zero Two
What a strange person.
Kokoro
I wonder if she likes sweets.
Miku
She's not a person. Not with
those things on her head.
Cut it out.
Ichigo
She's our savior, you know.
Ikuno
Do you think she really has klaxosaur blood?
Besides, I thought nobody
had single-digit codes.
She's nothing like the rumors said.
Goro
Futoshi
She's ruining her good looks
with the way she's eating.
Hiro
I can't believe all her
injuries healed so quickly.
Hey, there!
Zorome
It was a real treat to watch
your skills in action.
I, Zorome the Great, shall graciously
ride with you if you so desire.
I'm sure I can do a much
better job than that wuss.
Mitsuru
Why don't we try... Eek!
What do you think you're doing?!
Aw, my Sunday best!
What are you gonna do about this?!
This is really nice and sweet.
Let's eat together, okay?
Tell me.
Did I actually manage to pilot back then?
You sure did.
You were incredible,
darling.
D...
Darling?
What's that mean?
Beats me.
Do you know?
Hey! Don't ignore me!
Doesn't sound like food.
I wonder what it is.
Well, duh.
I see.
So I really did pilot that FRANXX back then!
Okay, keep it down, kids.
Nana!
I'll be your caretaker,
just like I was in Garden.
APE HQ has assigned me to the
13th Plantation Corps. My name is Nana.
APE Strategic HQ Parasite Caretaker  |  Nana
I look forward to your cooperation.
Yes! We got lucky!
Yay!
Thanks!
Nana...
Figures.
What is it, Ichigo?
For real?
Is she going to stay here?
We're awaiting orders from HQ
on what to do with Zero Two.
But in general, she won't
be working with you guys.
Come. You're sitting over here.
Aw, but this table felt more comfortable.
W-Wait!
Hey, Zero Two!
Let me ride in your FRANXX again.
There's something I want to be sure of.
That isn't for you to decide.
Papa and the rest will give you
your orders in due time, too.
Sit tight until then, all right?
Papa will?
Give orders to him? Why?
What was with that girl?
We can't have you running off
as you please all the time.
I just wanted to eat with my darling.
Avoid making contact with the parasites.
You're too much for them to handle.
I feel like I'm gonna suffocate in here.
Confirmed appearance of one
Mohorovicic-class klaxosaur at Plantation 13.
Strelizia intercepted and neutralized it.
Fuel stockpile down to 54 percent.
Currently anchored in the area.
Requesting kissing with Plantation 26.
APE Central HQ Council
Authorized.
Lamarck Club
Roger.
Kissing will commence in 175 hours.
We've received word that Strelizia
has stayed back at Plantation 13.
Another of that girl's whims?
Dr. Franxx spoils her too much.
But in this case, if you
just look at the numbers,
it seems to be a rare sample
without signs of physical aging.
It's Code 016. That's him, isn't it?
Unthinkable.
With no established cause, mixing with the
special specimen will taint her blood.
She must be recalled at once.
But we saw how she shone in that battle.
It's worth investigating.
Let's wait and see.
I'm amazed you managed
to fight that klaxosaur.
How was it?
I don't remember anything about it.
But I remember how it felt.
I see.
Either way, I'm glad you stayed.
Maybe you're the type that comes
through when it matters most.
Man, you got the jump on me.
Out of my way, dude.
I don't believe for a second that
you piloted a FRANXX before we did.
Got that, you wuss?
Jeez, why are these so tiny?
So tight!
Connecting feels so weird.
I hope we get used to it soon.
It's not at all like how
our training units felt.
It's like your body being
stirred up from the inside.
Hey, Miku!
Here it comes! Are you ready?
Stop reminding me of it.
Was it really that rough for you guys?
It did feel a bit weird, but I dunno...
It kinda put me at ease,
like I'd become one with someone.
What?
Wow.
I wish my numbers were as high as yours.
You and Goro must be really compatible.
Good for you. You two double-digit
elites are made for each other.
Gee, thanks.
Speaking of elite, how about that Hiro?
He brings home a girl out of nowhere,
and she's already calling him "darling."
Maybe those two will actually
make a good coup-
Wh-What was that all about?
I'll be giving out your overall
strategic instructions.
But the decisions on the field must be
made by the leader unit, Delphinium.
Roger.
Why does she get to be leader?
APE Strategic HQ Plantation Defense Commander  |  Hachi
If you're ready, we will now begin the drill.
This will be your first drill
in a real FRANXX, but stay calm,
focus on your partner's movements,
and entrust yourself to them.
Commence connecting.
Here it is!
Q-Quit making weird noises!
It's a natural reaction!
If two partners are even
slightly out of sync,
their para-capacity will fluctuate wildly.
The key is to trust your partners
and accept them wholeheartedly.
You okay?
I'm fine. Keep going.
Did I do it right? I didn't suck?
Nah, you were fine.
We're perfectly matched, huh?
FXX
Genista
Chlorophytum
Whoa, quit getting all
lovey-dovey over this crap.
FXX
Argentea
I was the first to finish, you know.
Got that, double-digits?
FXX
Delphinium
And don't you forget it.
Well, he's in high spirits.
What's the point of competing
among ourselves?
Hah! Sour grapes, much?
Hup! Unf!
H-Hey, don't be rough!
Huh?
Wh... Whoa!
You okay?
Thanks.
The stamen has the initiative
when it comes to handling,
so consider whether the pistil,
who's connected to the FRANXX, can keep up.
Thanks, Miss High-and-Mighty.
Line up in formation with Delphinium
in the center and advance.
Roger!
I did manage to pilot back then.
If I could just ride with
Zero Two in Strelizia again,
I...
A startup trial in an actual FRANXX?
Plantation FRANXX Parking Dock
I'm this close to figuring out
the trick to connecting.
Hey, tell me something.
Why'd it have to be Hiro?
Hiro? You mean my darling?
There you go, calling him that again.
I'm grateful to you for
defeating that klaxosaur.
But I want you to stay away
from Hiro from now on.
Why?
Because you're not part of our squad.
If you're gonna up and leave one day,
don't get Hiro's hopes up.
Oh?
What are you to my darling?
I'm the leader of this squad.
Hmm...
H-Hey...
Sweet. I like your taste.
Will we be able to fight like that one day?
Fight the klaxosaurs like the
FRANXX Hiro piloted, I mean.
Say what? Just so you know,
that doesn't count as piloting.
There's no way that loser
could pilot a FRANXX.
But it did actually move around.
And Papa seems to have taken
an interest in Hiro, too.
Well...
I hear that pistil called Zero Two
has the special ability to
pilot a FRANXX by herself.
You two saw its four-legged form, didn't you?
So basically, Hiro was only
taken along for the ride.
See? I'll never accept
that he did it before us.
Don't think you're hot stuff, you hear me?
Bingo! I'm the best!
Sorry about that. I really
expected you to dodge.
Were you cranking one out
all by yourself in a training unit?
That's perfect for you,
a wuss who just hitched a ride with a girl!
What? You wanna go?
Zero Two said I piloted that thing.
The real thing ain't anything
like the training units!
Once I get another chance,
I'll show you I can pilot!
Challenge accepted!
Hey, what are you doing?
Come on!
Knock it off.
Don't get in the way!
Enough!
Just calm down!
Damn you! You're nothing but a loser!
Don't let him get to you.
Lemme go!
I can pilot, too. I just need a chance.
Tch.
Hiro...
It's Nana.
A mock battle with me in a FRANXX?
That's right.
Depending on how you do,
we're considering promoting you to parasite.
Grats!
Pick your partner.
I'll do it.
Zero Two...
I mean, you are my darling.
One moment.
Let me be his partner.
Ichigo?
She doesn't belong to our squad.
Also, if you're only
measuring Hiro's aptitude,
it should work with me as his partner, too.
Then why does it have to be you?
You already have Goro as a partner,
and you want to ride with Hiro?
Pipe down.
Don't go running your mouths now.
Zero Two, HQ hasn't authorized
the use of Strelizia.
So Hiro will have to take the test
with someone from his squad.
Boo. That sucks.
Fine. My injuries haven't
healed completely yet, anyway.
Wait, what?
I'll let you have him this time. Go for it.
Take care of my darling, okay?
Then you'll handle it, right, Ichigo?
Sure.
Wait!
Does anyone want to volunteer
as their opponents?
Me!
Ack!
Hey, who died and made you boss?
I'm gonna show 'em what I'm capable of.
We'll do it.
Done deal.
The battle will be held tomorrow morning.
Wait, wait, wait!
Let us do it right now!
Zorome's still mad about your fight today.
Sorry. I know Ichigo's your partner.
Everything ready?
Yeah, I have to go.
Sure. See you later.
And Hiro, don't worry about it.
She never takes no for an answer.
I'm going to make this chance count.
Yeah. I know you can do it.
Hey, wuss! Let's settle the
score once and for all!
Given who your partner is, I might
just beat you this time, Great Leader.
Feel free.
This isn't about winning or losing, anyway.
Miku's totally up for it, too.
This isn't about winning.
I must prove to everyone that
Hiro can pilot the FRANXX!
Just focus on connecting, Hiro.
I'll take care of the rest.
Got it.
Begin the mock battle.
We're good to go.
Focus.
It'll be all right. I can draw
out Hiro's ability, too.
This feeling...
I'm entering Ichigo's mind.
It's all right. Keep going.
Got you!
Are you for real?
We did it!
Way to go, Hiro!
Huh...
Wow!
But...
This is where things get real.
This is it! I recognize this sensation!
Let's do this, Hiro!
Yeah!
Bring it on!
What?!
What's going on?
They stopped?
No... Why?
This can't be!
Time out! Give us three minutes!
What?!
You can't just call timeout!
Why'd it stop?
Move! Move!
Damn it! Why is this happening?
I was able to pilot back then!
What's wrong?
I don't know. It just stopped.
Was it my fault?
I don't think so.
What did she do differently?
I don't know. I don't remember.
Calm down. No need to rush.
You might remember something.
The kiss...
Maybe it was the kiss.
"Kiss"? What's that?
We stuck our mouths together,
and everything turned bright, like, "Wham!"
What the heck?
That's what you were up to
during a klaxosaur attack?
It wasn't me!
She did it as soon as I got in.
I didn't understand what she was doing,
but Zero Two said it was
a very special thing.
Fine. Let's do it.
It's embarrassing, so keep your eyes closed.
W-Wait a second!
We can't move unless we do it, right?
U-Uh...
If that's what it takes,
I don't mind. This is nothing.
But...
Shut up.
Ichigo, you're trembling...
Hey, hasn't it been three minutes already?
Yeah. I don't see why we gotta wait any more.
Sorry, but we're taking you out.
Well?
I don't feel a thing.
Looks like it didn't work.
Hey, this is too easy.
Let's try it again, Hiro.
Guess this proves that I'm really the best.
I don't mind taking over as
pilot for the Delphinium, too!
Excuse me?
You're hitting on another girl now?
Cut it out already, dude!
Huh?
The trust between partners has a
direct influence on the handling.
Should it be thrown out of whack...
What's going on?
Move...
Status report, Ichigo.
Ichigo?
Get it up already!
Shut up! I'm trying!
Ichigo, don't!
Piloting a FRANXX alone is dangerous!
Damn it all!
Of all the reckless stunts...
Since both FRANXX have been rendered
inoperable, this mock battle is over.
The gentle touch of her trembling lips
filled me with guilt.
The feeling that I'd gotten to fly back then
quickly slipped through my fingers
and eventually shackled me
to the ground once again.
It felt like I was being bound up
in a thousand invisible threads.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
You were awful.
Episode 2
What It Means to Connect