Of all the heavy-handed measures to take...
We wanted to eliminate all irregularities
before this important operation.
That is all.
If you keep doing this,
there's no guarantee that the
children will remain obedient.
Don't worry.
We haven't done anything to any
Squad 13 members but those two.
But why?
Since they're all together,
we decided to rid the parasites of
all unneeded emotions and memories.
Why wasn't I consulted?
Werner, please just behave for now.
You wished to see this plan come
to fruition too, you know.
They don't hesitate to use forceful
means to achieve their ends.
But I'm no different.
2025 A.D.
Mr. Werner...
Don't just walk in here!
The chancellor asked me to get you.
APE?
Surely you've heard of them.
Werner Frank
What does that upstart group want with me?
They say they want to hire you.
They're very impressed by your research.
My research? Which part?
Ask them for details when you're there.
I accepted their offer.
You accepted?
That's right.
Without asking me?
You show no signs of ceasing your illegal
experiments, chief among them cloning.
The community is up in arms against you.
You call them illegal,
but the law only ever cracks
down after I'm done.
There's no presumptive law because nobody
expected a heathen like you to show up.
Well, I am an atheist.
This is a matter of ethics.
You can't deny that I'm producing results.
Sure. I admit that you're vastly talented.
But I find you terrifying.
Me? Terrifying?
APE, a group of scientists with no
known origins or nationalities.
A mysterious organization that operated
with the Lamarck Club at its core.
They introduced revolutionary
mining technology,
dug up magma energy from underground
reserves far deeper than man had ever ventured,
and created a new energy source that
was both all-encompassing and low-cost.
With this energy revolution,
humanity drastically sped up its progress
toward the apex of material civilization.
At the same time, APE gained huge influence
in international politics and the economy.
Pardon me for being presumptuous,
but you're Werner Frank, aren't you?
That's right.
I knew it! It's an honor to meet you!
Is it?
It is! I've read all the
papers you've published!
Oh, I haven't introduced myself.
Karina Milsa
I'm Karina Milsa.
"Karina Milsa"?
The Karina Milsa of regenerative
telomere medicine fame?
That's me!
Do you have a problem with the contract?
No.
I was just surprised by
the amount of funding.
It's simply a fair valuation of your talents.
But to be honest, what you expect from me
is somewhat outside my field of expertise.
With your abilities, you should be
able to contribute more than enough.
Immortality...
Magma energy can even make that a reality.
Magma energy?
It was more than just an ideal energy source.
They said magma energy could even
put immortality within our reach.
Who would ever believe such a tall tale?
But any scientist who said it didn't
pique their curiosity would be lying.
2030 A.D.
We're not seeing any indicators of aging.
Right.
We did it!
So the research was a success?
I believe that's a safe assumption.
We couldn't have done it
without Dr. Frank's help.
You don't seem very happy about this.
Don't I?
Is something bothering you?
I'm only guessing,
but mankind might lose its reproductive
functions in exchange for its immortality.
We don't have any evidence indicating that.
No matter how we improve
ourselves with science,
we can't make up for the inherent
frailty of our bodies and minds.
More than anything,
it strips us of all beauty.
Are you saying it would be wrong
for mankind to attain immortality?
I wouldn't go that far.
I've always wanted to know our pinnacle,
our limit, as an organism.
I might still find that answer in our
evolutionary process post-immortality.
But will we be able to call
what we become "human"?
Do you mean we'd be gods?
I'm an atheist, you see.
Not long after that, it did indeed become
clear that the immortality procedure
led to the loss of reproductive functions.
But many people still made the
choice to become immortal.
Around that time, mankind recovered
from its rut thanks to magma energy
and quickly approached the
apex of material civilization.
But the only ones to benefit from it were
the rich, with access to immortality.
The class divide continued to grow ever wider.
Some years later, to combat the population
explosion resulting from immortality,
a law was passed in East Asia
to heavily tax childbirth.
It was the first step toward mankind
abandoning its procreative instincts.
At the same time,
rapid desertification was observed in
the southern parts of North America.
Some identified the mining
of magma energy as the cause,
but naturally, they were ignored.
This is really important!
I feel bad for you, but you're
not changing my mind!
What were you talking about?
Oh, you saw that?
Sorry. I didn't mean to.
Futoshi doesn't want to
be my partner anymore.
He says he'll team up with Ikuno,
and he wants me to team up with you.
But why?
It's too sudden, right?
They keep telling us about all this
stuff that happened between us,
but we don't remember any of it.
And even if they are telling the truth,
I don't believe I'll ever
develop those feelings for you.
Yeah.
It's probably the same for me.
2036 A.D.
At this point, humanity's immortality
rate already exceeded 70 percent.
And the rest were scheduled to complete
their procedures within two years.
But I...
You still can't bring yourself
to undergo the procedure?
I don't like having my body messed with.
If I'm forced to, I would much prefer
to replace it with a mechanical one.
Don't you think it's about time you stopped
to think about your life and future?
Stop it. You know that's not my style.
What about you? Aren't you
going to go under the knife?
No.
I want to have a child, actually.
Oh?
Is that surprising?
I just didn't think you had a partner.
He's pretty dense, so he
hasn't noticed my feelings.
If you're in love with someone,
shouldn't you ask him out to dinner instead?
I did.
Oh, so you did what you could.
Don't you think you're being a bit too dense?
It's me?
You have terrible taste.
But I guess I don't really mind.
By that time, desertification had become
a serious issue across the globe,
and APE presented to nations its plantation
project, which would be humanity's ark.
It essentially became the
leader of the whole world.
2037 A.D.
Offshore Magma Energy Mine
That year, it appeared in front of mankind.
Crying like a newborn baby,
it destroyed the mining facility
and proceeded to make landfall,
only stopping after several
nuclear missiles hit it.
As a result, the eastern half of the Australian
continent became an exclusion zone.
Soon, the beings designated
klaxosaurs, for "screaming reptiles,"
started showing up periodically everywhere.
It became clear that they were
attracted to magma energy mines, too.
The plantations turned into mobile
anti-klaxosaur fortresses,
cities were abandoned,
and mankind disappeared from the surface.
Where are you going?
It seems they've secured a decently
preserved klaxosaur corpse in Alaska.
But we're supposed to submit our
marriage registration next week.
If I'm not back by then,
go ahead and submit it.
I was enthralled.
The body's composition could be
called both mechanical and organic,
and it struck me as extremely beautiful.
Eventually, I noticed that it contained the
same XX chromosomes seen in female humans.
I didn't know what that indicated,
but I had a bad feeling about it.
My research was recognized,
and I was appointed lead developer
of an anti-klaxosaur weapon.
That robot was called a FRANXX.
2042 A.D.
Startup Trial for the Anti-Klaxosaur FRANXX Prototype
Number Thirteen
After FRANXX development finally
reached the prototype stage,
it hit a prolonged roadblock
where it wouldn't start up.
After rigorous testing
under various conditions,
it was discovered that the pilot needed
to still possess reproductive functions.
You didn't have to volunteer
to pilot yourself.
You have a valuable test
subject right under your nose.
It'd be a waste not to use her.
Sorry, and thanks.
Don't look at me like that.
See you later, then.
Is this a curse?
The tests continued,
and many lives were sacrificed.
The pilots were put under extreme stress.
By injecting them with yellow blood cells
that acted as a conduit to the FRANXX
and having them ride in male-female pairs,
that stress was found to be alleviated.
After losing its reproductive functions,
mankind ironically found
a need for new children.
As parasites, pilots of the FRANXX,
they were called "children,"
and they were made to refer
to the rest of us as adults.
Those two didn't just have
their memories erased.
They were also implanted
with elaborate, fake memories.
Are their real memories lost forever?
This is messed up.
Was what they did so bad that they
deserved to have their memories erased?
I'm sure Papa has his reasons.
Zorome, are you serious?
They destroyed everything about the
wedding we worked so hard for!
Yeah, sure, but we've only
ever had Papa our whole lives.
This isn't like you! I thought
you were better than that!
Oh, Hiro. How's Zero Two?
She's fine. She just needs
to get some final tune-ups.
I'm thinking of directly asking Papa
to return Mitsuru and Kokoro to normal.
Let's tell him how we feel.
In the initial usage phase of the FRANXX,
entire squads would die off,
taking the klaxosaurs down with them.
But we pushed on and succeeded in developing
weapons that worked on klaxosaurs.
After massive sacrifices, we started
formulating an effective way to kill them.
The Garden was founded as a
facility to nurture the children.
And the plantations were fitted with a
quarantine zone for parasites, Mistilteinn.
It was because parasites needed emotions,
and we'd found that antiquated environments
were best suited to raising them.
Their health is monitored in extreme detail,
and everything is controlled to
keep them in the best possible shape.
Eventually, the humans holed up inside
the plantations, the "adults,"
forgot about the existence of klaxosaurs,
and under the influence of magma energy
and their immortality treatments,
they obtained a life of eternal tedium.
I was looking for somewhere I belonged,
a resting place for my heart.
By this time, my interest in the
future of mankind had faded,
and I engrossed myself in research,
seeking a more perfected lifeform.
That's when a strange rumor
started making the rounds.
A rumor that said the klaxosaurs
had a leader, a queen bee of sorts.
I don't know how, but APE discovered
where that leader was hiding.
You may go along, but on one condition.
One condition?
Should you encounter the klaxosaur queen,
bring back something, anything that
could serve as a DNA sample.
Shockingly,
we found waiting for us the remains
of an unknown, ancient civilization.
What are you doing here?
Who's there?
Ignorant beings, why are you here?
Why do you kill our brethren?
What's this voice? Where is it coming from?
You're wrong. It's transmitting
directly into our brains.
Klaxosaurs detected!
What? From which direction?
From all directions!
All directions?
Prepare for combat! Form a circle!
Your species is so needlessly belligerent.
One enemy, approaching at speed!
Don't kill that one. Bring it to me.
I was exhilarated.
She was without a doubt the most beautiful
thing I'd ever seen in my life.
Hold out your hand.
I smell my brethren on you.
It seems your sins are far too grave
to be punished with mere death.
Even as she bit off my arm,
I remained entranced by klaxosaurs
and remained in love with
the klaxosaur princess.
I might really have already
lost all of my humanity.
Begone! And tell your kind not to
lay a hand on my brethren anymore!
What is it?
We have a request.
Return Mitsuru-
Return Code 326 and Code 556's
memories to normal.
That's impossible.
We didn't seal off their memories.
We removed the unnecessary information.
There's no way to bring them back.
No...
What you're currently doing is
a severe breach of protocol.
Ordinarily, you would be punished,
but given your accomplishments, we'll let
you off with a mere mention on your record.
Return to your waiting quarters at once.
Please wait...
Apologize! Apologize, damn it!
Futoshi?!
How can you act so carefree after
erasing someone's precious memories?!
Stop it! Don't get emotional!
Don't try to sweep this under the rug!
Look at least a little sorry
for what you've done!
Would it kill you to utter
one damn apology?!
Um, can you tell us one thing?
What is it?
Please tell us...
How many more klaxosaurs do we have
to kill before we can become adults?
What are we living for, then?
Do we really only exist
to pilot FRANXX and die?
At least tell us that much, Papa!
Zorome...
You guys took away Zero Two's
and my precious memories
and did the same to Mitsuru and Kokoro.
We can't see you as our Papa anymore.
Once this battle is over, set us free!
Very well.
As long as you fulfill your duties
in the next mission, that is.
We're done here.
You rise up against fate?
Then show me
whether you kids can become
real humans or not.
We'll decide our fate ourselves.
I saw you in Zero Two's memories.
I will never forgive you for what you did.
Darling, you pervert.
Hey, Zero Two. We've made our decision.
Right.
Let's go, Zero Two.
Fate is cruel more often than not.
But at times, it can be quite
powerless in the face of desire.
Zero Two, you would probably
hate me if you knew.
Soon...
Soon, my dream will come true.
Show me your perfected form,
and how beautiful it can be!
Episode 19
Inhumanity