World War III.
By 2036,
it will have resulted in 5.7 billion casualties worldwide.
And this is what starts it.
Huh? What is it?
It's only a model.
Maybe it transforms or something?
A time machine.
Seriously?
I knew you'd recognize it, Uncle.
Then that makes this easy.
Come with me.
I refuse...
Okarin?
I've come here from the alpha world line.
Over the past three weeks,
I changed that world line again and again,
sacrificing Kurisu to return here,
to the beta world line.
I can't let all of that count for nothing!
Kurisu-san?
Kurisu?
Wasn't that the name of the scientist
who was stabbed at the Radio Building?
Okabe Rintarou,
what if I told you that the way
to avoid World War III
is to prevent Makise Kurisu's death
on July 28th, 2010?
What do you mean?
I don't know the details.
But I have one mission...
To save Makise Kurisu,
and to go to the one world line unaffected
by the Attractor Field:
The Steins Gate!
inochi no shuchou to muimi no shoumei
Pet theories and meaningless proofs
anata ni wa taikutsu shinogi ni taranu koukei
Are not enough to keep you amused
shihaisha kidori no orokana shuzoku wa
Those conceited fools who pretend to be kings
unuboreta chisetsuna teiri wo narabeta
Lay down their childish theorems
mugen to shinjita ai mo sora no kanata mo
The infinite love and the distant reaches of the sky
bokutachi ni shimesareta kasou no jiyuu
Are but virtual liberties revealed to us
yuugen sore wa mujihi ni toki wo kizami
Finitude is the ruthless passage of time
asu sae mo hitei suru sentaku e
Make the choice to deny even tomorrow
Hacking to the Gate
ikutsu mo no kagayakeru hibi nakama to no yakusoku
We must never destroy those promises to our comrades
nakatta koto ni wa shite wa ikenai
Or those many happy days together
sono tame ni toki wo azamuku
For that is why we cheat time
nokosareta shikake ni mou mayoi wa nai
We have doubt in our devices no more
kodoku no kansokusha
A lonely observer
Open the
Steins Gate
Steins Gate?
The architects of this plan were
my father and your future self.
None of it is anything more than a hypothesis.
It's possible the theory is wrong,
and there is no Steins Gate world line.
But I'm going anyway.
I'll bet on the chance that
a bright future's waiting for me.
If you're coming with me,
then take my hand.
Um,
Mayushii didn't really understand any of that.
But if this person,
this Kurisu-san, is important to you,
shouldn't you try to help them?
World War III sounds too much
like one of your fantasies.
No one else could handle it.
I don't care about 5.7 billion people in the future.
But...
Thank you.
Board now.
Two people can get in it?
Of course!
This is my father's masterpiece.
Okarin!
Leave your phone.
It might get crossed with your
phone in the past.
I'll return.
Good luck.
This is a time machine.
Yeah,
I stopped in 1975 and 2000.
It's working fine.
But it's running out of fuel...
Wait, it can go from past to future?
Of course it can.
It's a time machine.
I see...
Is that because we're in a different world line now?
Sit down.
We'll head to just before noon, on July 28th.
We can't change location,
so if we arrive too early, it'll spread
panic at the Radio Building,
possibly affecting Makise Kurisu's actions.
Your first time, the Gs are pretty tough.
Get ready.
Okarin...
What is this?
These always show up.
I guess they're like fragments of time.
Pretty, huh?
Let's go!
W-Wait.
I think I'm going to throw up...
You're a wimp...
Hurry!
Don't let your other self encounter you.
It'll cause a serious time paradox.
How long until her stabbing?
Twenty minutes or so, I guess.
I'll ready the time machine.
You protect her, Uncle.
Stop calling me that.
July 28th.
The day I saw Kurisu lying in a pool of blood,
I'd come with Mayuri to see
Professor Nakabachi's press conference.
I heard a noise on the roof.
That's right. After this, Mayuri goes
to the 7th-floor Upa machines.
Oh, no!
You called me here for this?
There aren't many left of this series,
and Mayushii's...
Oh well.
I'll take the back stairs to the 8th floor.
It's a metal... A metal Upa!
Is it rare?
Really!
If I make it here...
I'm sorry.
K-Kurisu?
H-How do you know my name?
Kurisu is alive...
Have we met somewhere?
Kurisu...
Are you listening...
What's wrong?
Answer me.
I... You...
Professor Nakabachi's press conference will start shortly in the eighth floor theatre.
Wait!
In the handouts, you can read about
the time machine's basic design.
I will use this conference as an opportunity
to discuss the fundamental theory behind it.
Professor Nakabachi
The operation notes said that
you'd be able to identify Makise Kurisu.
Can you do it?
Yeah.
Also, it's dangerous to take her outside.
If we can't find and neutralize the cause of her stabbing,
the probability of a fatal outcome is high.
The same as with Mayuri?
Doctor!
What is it?
You know exactly what!
What is this "time machine theory" of yours?
Kerr Black Holes?
World lines?
You stole all this from John Titor!
Kurisu will be stabbed right here soon.
Is she really going to be here?
Wait! Maybe she was stabbed elsewhere
and brought here.
Yeah... That's possible!
Kurisu?
So, it does happen here.
What's she reading?
A time machine?
Is that why she's the key to changing world lines?
What do you want?
Daddy, I wanted you to read this.
Daddy?
Professor Nakabachi?
You contacted me for the first time in seven years.
You asked me to come to
your press conference, right?
That was my inspiration...
Wait, so Kurisu's dad is...
So I thought I could use it to theorize a time machine.
I wanted to hear your theories.
If this is accepted, you can use it
to show everyone who kicked you out of academia...
I wasn't kicked out!
I got sick of them and left.
Sorry...
It's not bad.
Really?
If you're okay with it,
I thought we could put both
our names on the paper.
Because you inspired me...
Don't be stupid.
Leave!
I'll publish this paper under my name.
Wait!
You wouldn't steal it, right, Daddy?
I thought, no matter what, you'd never do that...
Shut up!
How dare you call it stealing!
Why are you so smart?
A girl shouldn't be smarter than her father!
If it weren't for you, I'd have been smart, too!
If it weren't for you...
I...
You're that kid from earlier.
So that's it?
You were plotting to ruin
my conference together, right?
I see...
So that's it.
Daddy!
I'll protect her!
How dare you insult me?
Why, you...
Stop it, Daddy!
Please!
Don't even speak to me!
Oh no!
What do you know?
You don't know how I feel.
You don't know how I've been humiliated...
The hell I've been through!
If it weren't for you...
Don't...
Don't do it!
Kurisu...
K-Kurisu!
Fools.
This is the perfect end for you.
I'm sorry for involving you...
Why?
Because he's my dad.
I wanted him to accept me.
That's all.
Kurisu...
I'm scared...
I... I don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
I don't...
Kurisu...
Kurisu!
They're back already!
Okarin!
Okarin, that blood...
It's all right.
It's not his.
I was the one who killed Kurisu...
Okarin?
I know it hurts, but you can't give up yet.
We have enough fuel to go back once more...
Shut up!
It'll just be the same!
The Attractor Field convergence will
kill her all over again.
It's your phone.
A message?
Open it.
But...
Just do it.
Turn on the TV.
Turn on the TV?
The TV?
Mysterious Fire in Cargo Bay
Professor Nakabachi
Defects to Russia
The plane carrying Professor Nakabachi
made it to Russia,
despite a mysterious cargo bay fire.
We were very fortunate.
If this hadn't triggered the metal detector,
Ma
yu
shii
the paper would have gone up.
That's Mayushii's metal Upa!
Look. It has Mayushii's name on it!
She's right.
But what's it doing in Russia?
That paper is the start of everything.
Next comes the international,
time machine arms race.
To rule time is to rule the world.
And that begins a world war.
5.7 billion lives are at stake.
Save Makise Kurisu, and change this world line!
It's impossible...
It's just like with Mayuri.
No matter what I do, it'll end up the same.
Kurisu will die.
How can you say that after only one time?
One time?!
It's more than that...
How many times...
How many times do you think I've failed?!
I can tell...
How insane this time loop is...
What a cruel fate it has in store...
I knew this...
I knew this would happen.
I'm tired.
I'm so tired...
You're not the kind of person to quit halfway.
Mayushii knows this!
You're not the kind of person to ever give up.
Even when Mayushii couldn't
say goodbye to her grandmother,
you never stopped going to her grave.
That's why I could say goodbye.
That's why I got better!
So don't give up.
You should have received a video file on July 28th.
July 28th...
You should be able to watch it,
now that you've failed once
to rescue Makise Kurisu.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry I lied to you.
The plan called for you to fail once.
So that you would see this.
What is this?
Nice to meet you, myself fifteen years ago.
It's Okarin!
If you've opened this message,
then you've failed to rescue Kurisu.
It must have been painful.
But that pain gave rise to my obsession.
So it had to happen.
You might say it was a part of the preparation.
Now we can begin the plan for real.
The plan to save Makise Kurisu,
and enter Steins Gate.
We have two objectives.
First, to destroy the paper on time machines,
which Professor Nakabachi took to Russia.
Second, to save Makise Kurisu.
If I could do that...
But avoiding her death and
changing the past are impossible
because of the Attractor Field convergence.
Right?
I'll be as clear as possible.
Saving Makise Kurisu is possible.
You're just approaching it the wrong way.
Listen well.
You must not change the past,
once it's been established.
You must not undo what you saw that day.
If you do either, the past will change,
and all will be lost.
Remember your experiences
in the alpha world line.
It was only three weeks,
but you should have memories
of your time with Makise Kurisu.
Of all you and she sacrificed to save Mayuri.
Of everything that happened.
You must not waste those three weeks.
You must not undo them.
The only reason you wish so desperately to save her
is because of the world lines you experienced.
And it's the sole reason
I devoted my life to developing a time machine.
The reason you've managed to get
as far as you have is that
we both want to save Kurisu.
So you must deceive your other self.
Save her without changing the past where she died.
Make your past self
mistake a living Kurisu for a dead one.
If you do, the past won't change.
I get it...
What does he mean?
Okarin, do you know?
I know you'll understand me.
By the way, the time machine's ID is C204.
I'm sure you know what that stands for.
Christina...
And I was the one who named
the target world line Steins Gate.
You know why I named it that.
It doesn't really mean anything.
Right?
I will now explain the parameters
of the final mission, Operation Skuld.
Change the result without changing
the established past.
The past consists of Makise Kurisu,
lying in a bloody pool,
and Okabe Rintarou seeing her there.
Change the past without changing that.
Deceive your other self.
Deceive the world.
That is what you must do to reach Steins Gate.
Good luck.
El Psy Congroo.
What was that?
Was that you, fifteen years from now?
The voice was so deep!
Operation Skuld?
El Psy Congroo?
I still talk like that when I'm thirty-three years old?
I sound like an otaku who's read too many bad light novels.
Okarin?
I'll do it.
If that is the choice of Steins Gate.
I am the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma!
Deceiving the world is nothing to me!
He's back to the usual Okarin.
But Mayushii likes Okarin better
when he's like this.
I'll say it once more.
I am the mad scientist, Hououin Kyouma...
And the world is in the palm of my hand!
sore wa oroka yue no guuzen
That's a set of foolish coincidences
manekarezaru kiseki
An uninvited miracle
tozasaretekita gate
The gate that's now closed
kisei wa owatta
The laws have broken down
Open the Eyes
kousoku e to te wo nobashita
We reached out at the speed of light
omoide no pulse ga tobikomu
A pulse of memories dive in
fukashigi na logic
An enigmatic logic
Open the Eyes
uchuu ga mata kakushimotta
Yet another chaotic theory
chitsujo no nai riron
Buried in the heavens
mugen to yobareta ten to ten ga, fusei na chikara wo karite
Those points called infinity take law-breaking powers
saisei wo suru
To bring about rebirth