You're going to die... Abandoned, still longing...
Four days. August 15th.
The world itself has decided that you will die.
There's no avoiding it.
But I won't let it happen.
I'll fight the world!
I will save Mayuri!
The coin locker...
In front of the Daibiru.
The IBN 5100...
suujuuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
Even the world's billions of heartbeats
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
Are nothing to you but a fleeting and insignificant question
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
We may be trapped in the past or lament the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
But predetermination does not allow the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and imagined futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
Are naught but vain theories we may hold
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what the two clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
As they point toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
And now I cross the boundary between worlds each second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
Because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no ruupu e to
And a loop in time without sadness will once again
nomikomarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Engulf me, a lonely observer
Finalize
Apoptosis
Okabe, what's wrong?
Okay! This'll...
Stop!
The IBN 5100 is in a coin locker.
Moeka told me...
It hasn't been recovered yet.
So?
What else?
I'll break the locker open with this!
Calm down.
Remember...
Remember what?!
Everything that's happened.
Despite all the D-mails you've undone,
you haven't recovered the IBN 5100.
Most likely, it's impossible until you get back
to the original world line.
And for that to happen, you have to do things in order.
It's so close...
But now, we have a clue.
Kiryuu Moeka will do whatever this FB says, right?
And FB's the... leader, right?
Then...
If I stake out the IBN 5100, maybe I'll see them.
What are you doing here?
Bread
I want to see FB, too...
Didn't you want to avoid seeing them?
Because they'd hate you or something?
I want to know... the truth.
What good will it do you?
I don't know.
Did you think I'd work with you?
Well, I guess I can talk to you.
What's wrong?
N-Nothing.
You're with Kiryuu Moeka?
Why?
She's...
That's just how it worked out.
If something happens, I'll tell you.
Hey, wait!
Jeez...
Was that Okarin?
Yeah.
What's wrong?
I feel like lately, Okarin and I haven't talked at all.
Mayuri-oneechan!
Nae-chan!
Hi there, assistant-oneechan!
It's Kurisu-oneechan.
Hi there.
Sorry about yesterday.
Tell Okabe his rent's going up 5,000 yen.
I-I will.
Actually, I haven't seen him today.
Did he get sick or something?
Though they say idiots don't get sick...
I think he's looking for stuff to use in his experiments.
Experiments, huh?
Lucky guy...
A student with his own damned room,
friends like you guys,
and who does whatever he wants...
He really is lucky.
But...
Daddy, if we don't hurry, we'll miss the sale!
Right! Let's go, Nae!
Bye-bye, onee-chans!
Bye-bye!
What do you want for dinner?
Um...
A message from FB?
Can I see it?
"I think M4 was right.
I think M4 was right.
To be honest, no one works as hard as M4.
To be honest, no one works as hard as M4."
M4?
The code name FB gave me.
Only FB and I know it.
It's a secret.
"That's true.
You may be bad at dealing with others, M4.
But that's part of what makes you you."
A mom, huh?
That's it...
The IBN 5100!
Then is he FB?
No.
FB is a woman.
I know him!
Damn it!
What's wrong?
I'll explain later.
Mister Braun?
So, have you driven since you got your license?
No.
Please drive safely.
Have you ever seen him before?
No.
What does this mean?
Four days. August 15th.
The world itself has decided that you will die.
There's no avoiding it.
A plane to France...
That's where SERN is.
We never saw any women who could have been FB.
At least give me a damned phone call!
I was busy.
Forget about me.
But...
Mayuri...
Come to think of it,
I think it's been a long time since we last spoke.
That's what she said, too.
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
We'll have to ask him directly.
Ask him...
Someone we know well.
What brings you here so early?
Come in.
So, what do you want?
Did you come to pay the extra 6,000 yen I added to your rent?
Hey, hey... You're supposed to say,
"That's 1,000 more yen than you said!"
There's something I'd like to ask you.
What? Why so formal?
You know someone named FB, don't you?
We saw it all.
And the IBN 5100 being taken from here as well.
We don't care about you.
We want to see FB.
Please tell me where they are.
You sold us out, M4.
The code name FB gave me.
Only FB and I know it.
Then...
What do you mean?
Ever heard of Ferdinand Braun?
The Nobel laureate who invented the Braun tube.
That's the guy.
And what are his initials?
F... B...
Then you're...
That can't be!
So you're following dependence with reality avoidance?
Nae is asleep.
Let's go somewhere else.
This town keeps changing.
Are you really FB?
Yes.
But those messages...
I wrote them all.
Why did I write like a woman?
To trick you.
Bu-
You weren't the only one.
I message the others, too,
in the guise of whomever they most need.
Of course, people like you are the easiest to trick, which helps.
Why break off contact with her?
The second she found the IBN 5100, I didn't need her anymore.
So I stopped talking to her.
We collect members through text messages.
People like that are the easiest to deal with.
And the easiest to get rid of when we're done.
There's nothing they belong to.
I can't believe you're SERN's dog...
Dog?
Suzuha... Hashida Suzu-san
didn't take care of you for that!
How do you know about Suzu-san?
Suzu-san has nothing to do with this...
Not a thing!
But...
What do you know?!
Ever sleep down a manhole, in the middle of winter?
I was still a kid.
The concrete was so cold,
it seeps into your bones.
I didn't eat for three or four days at a time.
And when I lay down,
they came.
Rats. They thought I was dead, and came to eat me.
And then, I saw a thread descend...
As thin as a spider's.
I had no choice but to climb it...
Even if, at the top,
I ended up dirtying my hands.
I kept climbing the thread.
And next thing I knew, I was a puppet on a string.
I couldn't escape.
Puppets who escape the thread...
Traitors die.
Well, once you complete your mission, you also die.
You called me a dog, didn't you?
I'm worse than a dog.
I'm cattle.
Sometimes, I thought of running.
But I have something I care about now.
I didn't want to involve them.
But failure isn't allowed.
If you run, they go after your family.
I failed, too.
But Nae doesn't know anything.
As long as I die.
Wait-
O-Okabe-ku...
Okabe-kun...
I-I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
O-Okabe... His phone!
The D-mail!
Okabe!
Stop searching for the IBN 5100, and return to stand by.
Do not act under any circumstances.
Moeka...
Shining Finger
(No Subject)
I won't need the IBN 5100 for a while.
Moeka
You won't need it?
Shining Finger
(No Subject)
My boss said to stop looking for it.
Moeka
Yes, this is Urushibara.
Kyouma-sa-
What? An IBN 5100?
Yes.
It's here...
Daru!
Hashida's not here.
He said he was going to Comima.
Please...
Hear my request!
I see...
To save Mayuri,
we need to get out of this alpha world line,
and return to the world line before you sent the first D-mail,
the beta world line.
For that to happen, we have to erase the information from SERN's database.
Mayushi dies, and Miss Amane is my daughter from the future.
If that's all a fantasy, I think Okarin could become a light novel author.
I wish that were true.
You believe it, Miss Makise?
As a hypothesis.
If feasible, I'd prefer some reliable, objective data.
But that's impossible.
The time leap machine you made worked perfectly.
D-Did it?
O-Of course it did!
And...
What?
Nothing.
Wh-What?
I said nothing.
It's connected.
I need to know the settings, but I can start in ten minutes.
I'm counting on you, super haker.
Super hacker.
The first D-mail, huh?
That's the one where I was stabbed or whatever, right?
Did you try to feel me up or something?
Erase all the D-mails, returning the world line to its original one.
The world line in which SERN doesn't establish a dystopia.
The world line in which Mayuri doesn't die.
And in that world line...
...Makise Kurisu...
...dies.
kisei sareta chikai mujihi naru, juuni no shinri nogarerarenai
We cannot escape the 12 merciless truths and the controlled oath we took
ansoku no asu wo negattara
If we wish for a tomorrow full of rest
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
to be given to the precious event horizon in our hands
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
the promise we made in captivity turns out to be a phantom
seimei no tenshi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
The angel of life recorded a time of blindness
habatake butterfly
A flapping butterfly
kiseki no butterfly
A miraculous butterfly
anata he sasageru
I will consecrate them to you
namida no butterfly
A butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
A radiant butterfly
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
Everything may now be rewritten