This is...
A time machine.
I'm from the year 2036.
Suzuha...
I am the time traveler
John Titor.
suujuuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
Even the world's billions of heartbeats
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
Are nothing to you but a fleeting and insignificant question
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
We may be trapped in the past or lament the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
But predetermination does not allow the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and imagined futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
Are naught but vain theories we may hold
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what the two clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
As they point toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
And now I cross the boundary between worlds each second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
Because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no ruupu e to
And a loop in time without sadness will once again
nomikomarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Engulf me, a lonely observer
Missing
Link Necrosis
The year 2036.
The world was ruled by SERN...
An oppressive, totalitarian society, a dystopia.
The people's freedom was stolen,
and they lived like zombies.
Anyone who disobeyed was killed.
I was part of the resistance,
fighting to free the world from SERN's control.
To change this dead world...
...I entered the time machine my father left me.
And to change the future.
Then, everything you wrote on @channel...
Yes, most of it was true.
But SERN is a research organization,
not a ruling body.
On the net, I told John Titor that many times.
Wait!
Does that mean you
are Chestnut Rice and Kamehameha?
Titor identified himself,
so it wouldn't be fair not to identify myself, too...
Then I'll identify myself, as well.
I was using the handle Hououin Kyouma...
We know that.
SERN succeeded in developing a time machine.
By becoming the only ones able to
interfere with the fourth dimension, time,
they remade the entire world map.
And Makise Kurisu is the person
who contributed the most to the time machine's development.
She's worshipped as the mother of the time machine.
I worked with SERN?
No way!
Why would I work with the kind of people who
perform human experiments?
That's what happened in the future.
So that's why you hated me...
Then, what about the future me?
Okabe Rintarou is a famous terrorist.
Terrorist?
A terrorist who fought SERN.
And you're both...
dead in the year 2036.
I need to hurry.
Wait.
You're saying something crazy like that,
and returning to the future?
That's why I'm leaving.
I'm going to the past, to change that future.
To 1975...
1975?
SERN succeeded in developing the time machine,
due to the time machine created in 2010, in Akihabara.
You mean the Phone Microwave?
SERN used a communications monitoring system
to gather all the information they could on time machines, from around the world.
I think the first D-mail you sent tripped the system.
The message I sent in front of the Radio Building?
Yes.
So if we delete the message from SERN's database,
the future will change.
We can go to the beta world line, where SERN
never successfully created a time machine.
Will that save Mayuri?
I think so.
Then we should start hacking SERN's database immediately...
We need the IBN 5100 for that.
I see. So that's why...
My task was to go to 1975,
find an IBN 5100,
and get it to Okabe Rintarou.
But I stayed too long, looking for my father.
I should have gone earlier.
Is everything okay?
No...
It's broken.
This is bad!
What do we do?
I'll think of something.
You hide.
As soon as you can, run.
Anyone here?
Who's there?
Stay back!
I'm in the midst of an operation
to end the Organization's schemes!
This is a level-70 top-secret mission.
So stay away from this place!
This way! Hurry!
Hey!
Wait!
We're running.
Hurry!
I don't know what happened in the future,
but right now, I'm a lab member, just like you!
Okabe!
You're safe?
Let's go!
What do we do?
We can't go back there.
Was the time machine broken?
Was it from when it crashed into the roof?
It didn't crash.
There was an error in calculating the coordinates,
where it appeared.
When I arrived, it wasn't broken.
Then when?
If I had to guess, I'd say that thunderstorm we had...
It might have been hit by lightning, or flooded...
It's my fault.
Because I stopped you then...
I'll use the time leap machine...
We can only use it to go back 48 hours.
We can't get back to that night.
Okarin!
And Kurisu-chan and Suzu-san are with you!
You didn't go home?
Mayushii said we should have a party to celebrate
the time machine's completion.
Daru-kun and I went shopping!
I said we were done for the day!
I'm sorry, Mayuri.
We have to talk about something important.
Okarin?
Just go home for today.
We'll have the party another time.
All right.
But don't do anything dangerous.
Mayushii is worried.
It'll be fine.
I promise.
See you tomorrow, then!
Yeah.
I heard the trains stopped.
Seriously?
We'll have to repair the time machine.
First, go back five hours ago,
to when the time leap machine was completed.
From there, go back 48 hours.
To 2:00 PM, on the 11th.
That's the most time we have.
I'll finish the time machine during those two days,
no matter what.
If I can't, I'll redo those two days as many times as it takes.
This isn't to save the world.
It's a mission to save Mayuri.
Okabe?
What's wrong?
Gather all the lab members right away.
There's something I want to talk to them about.
Future tech is awesome.
This must be photoshopped.
Can you fix it?
Miss Amane, you can't do it yourself?
It's too much for me.
My father's the one who made it.
There's no way we can fix a time machine
from 2036, using today's technology.
We won't know until we try.
Anyway, try and do it in two days, Daru.
You're our only hope.
Why two days?
Well...
Just do it!
If you can, I'll do anything you want.
Teacher, I want to have a day-long date with Feyris-tan!
All right, I'll make it happen somehow.
No, that's impossible.
I can do anything!
Believe in me.
You're serious? For real?
I promise.
So do it.
Very well!
One more thing, okay?
If I fix it, in addition to the IBN 5100,
get me a cel from the legendary
1975 magical girl anime, Ragical Girl Omit-chan!
Shut up.
Should I help, too?
No, you need to finish the time leap machine.
We should get back to the lab.
Hey, aren't you all forgetting something?
Looking for Suzu-san's dad.
I'm all right...
No, you're not!
You got in the time machine
because you had a job to do,
but also because you wanted to see your dad, right?
So Mayushii wants to help you find him.
Your dad's name was Barrel Titor, right?
That was his code name.
I don't know his real name.
What's Amane?
My mom's name.
My only clue is this little badge he had.
Your dad is in 2010 Akihabara, right?
Okay, Mayushii will be the investigator.
Shiina Mayuri... She's a good girl, isn't she?
Think you can fix it?
No way to say for sure yet.
But when I looked at it, I realized...
It's kind of like the Phone Microwave.
Then it's possible you can fix it, right?
I wonder if your dad's nearby.
He knew that we were in Akiba, in 2010, right?
I think so.
But I never heard from him directly.
I've never met him.
Everything was in his will.
My dad was researching a time machine,
separately from SERN...
To change the future.
I'm here to carry on, in his place.
I really am sorry...
But it might be that, if I can fix the time machine,
we'll find your dad before you get back from 1975.
So keep this a secret from Okarin,
and try to get me that cel...
That's a pretty straightforward way to do it.
Supposedly, we're the future gadget lab.
I guess you don't have a more futuristic way?
Nothing so convenient.
Future Gadget #2, Alt. Edition,
Version 2.67.
AKA The Bamboo Copter Camera.
There's a CCD camera on the lower body.
Surprisingly sane.
Could we use this for an aerial search?
The camera spins, too,
so the video you receive revolves at a high speed.
You're at version 2.67, and that still isn't fixed?
That's the first one we've made.
Daru came up with the name, along with the version.
There's no real meaning.
Where's Daru?
He's still there, working.
The Divergence Meter...
You made it. I think you should have it.
If this number goes above 1%, the future will change.
You're the only one who will know,
with your Reading Steiner.
Did I give you that, before I died in the future?
No, I've never met you.
You were a founding member of the resistance I was in.
I founded a resistance?
How stupid.
I couldn't even save Mayuri.
And I kept on living!
Acting like a stupid little kid, with his fantasies?
It wasn't stupid!
It was an honest, brave desire to save the world!
Hey, mister...
I am mad scientist!
It's so cool!
Sonuvabitch.
Hi, what is it?
So, Japanese works, huh?
There's something I want to ask you.
Ever seen this before?
I want to know where it came from.
Can you look into it for me?
The remember.
Sorry. It is difficult.
You sure about that Japanese working?
If you remember, contact me here.
Maybe this will be created in the near future,
but doesn't exist now?
I may be fated to not meet my dad, after all.
Want to give up on it?
You're giving up?
We still have a day!
Why are you so mad-
I want to prioritize saving Mayuri!
Even so, you're a lab member and a friend.
I want to help you if I can!
So why are you already giving up?
D-Don't yell at me, okay?
I'm sorry.
Please!
What is she...
There was a kidnapping yesterday!
I'm looking for the criminal. He wore a badge like this!
Please help us!
Okarin!
Look! Look!
Mayuri...
Good idea, right?
It was Mayushii's idea!
I think everyone might go, "Huh?" when they see this.
This is operation:
Big Victory with Mayushii's Pamphlets!
I think a kidnapping is going too far, don't you?
What if the police start looking at us...
Oh, no! Run!
What?
Hey, you guys!
Wait!
I'm sorry.
From now on, ask me about these operations first,
including the name...
What are you doing?
Oh, it's Christina.
Good timing.
I learned something really bad.
What?
When I went to buy lunch, I overheard the clerks.
Amane-san's dad might be a kidnapper.
Wh-What?
What's going on?
How's it going?
Something to drink.
If you were awesome, you would've brought me
an ice-cold zero-calorie cola.
Well?
Can we fix the time machine?
Probably by tomorrow.
Even working this whole time, that's still amazing!
Daru's the real thing.
Even if he looks unhealthy and kind of dim.
Don't judge him by his looks.
Yeah. I've changed my mind about him.
Then you help me, too.
And then, in the steaming hot confines of the time machine,
we can forget our shame and take off our clothes...
Shut up, pervert!
Daru-kun and Suzu-san look good together.
Together? How?
I don't really know how to say it...
Just, somehow.
What's up?
Don't worry about it!
Mayuri was just saying something weird.
But if the time machine gets fixed,
I'm worried about Suzu-san when she rides it!
If it were for two, I could go with you...
Why would you go with her?
Why else?
I'd hold Suzu-san's hand really tight, and I'd say,
"It's okay! Mayushii's with you, so it's okay!"
Hey, I'm saying this because
I don't think I'll ever have the chance to say it again.
What? That's an exaggeration.
I'm really grateful to you all.
When I first came here, I didn't know anyone.
Even though this era is much more peaceful,
somehow, to me, it was really scary.
But now I have lots of friends.
I'm really happy that I could come here...
That I could spend time with you guys.
I'm glad I could be a lab member, just for a while.
I'm glad I could spend time with you...
Suzuha...
Okabe Rintarou! Change the future...
Make it a free world, like this one!
Suzuha?
Yes?
Hello?
Mad scientist so cool?
The guy from this morning?
I remembered...
About that pin badge from yesterday.
You found her father?
I'll be right there!
Wait!
kisei sareta chikai mujihi naru, juuni no shinri nogarerarenai
We cannot escape the 12 merciless truths and the controlled oath we took
ansoku no asu wo negattara
If we wish for a tomorrow full of rest
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
to be given to the precious event horizon in our hands
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
the promise we made in captivity turns out to be a phantom
seimei no tenshi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
The angel of life recorded a time of blindness
habatake butterfly
A flapping butterfly
kiseki no butterfly
A miraculous butterfly
anata he sasageru
I will consecrate them to you
namida no butterfly
A butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
A radiant butterfly
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
Everything may now be rewritten